Mikkel R. Davis

Web Developer Provo, UT

gh /in/ @ **mikkelrd** .com

mikkeld@gmail.com / 916 467 6776

DEV SKILLS

GIT + GITHUB HTML + CSS JAVAS HTTP + REST PASSPORT.js MONG

JAVASCRIPT + JQUERY MONGODB + MONGOOSE ANGULAR.js

FIREBASE

NODE.js + EXPRESS.js

PROJECTS

DEVMTN RESOURCES – Worked with team to develop full MEAN stack app according to customer specs, for use by web dev community to aggregate, browse, and rank learning resources.

RECUR — Web app for managing recurring monthly subscription services. Personally authored all code, using full MEAN stack. Researched and implemented cron-based email reminders.

PROVO DICTIONARY – Navigating Utah Valley can be difficult without familiarity with the local vocab. A special lexicon built using Angular, Firebase, and Bootstrap.

EXPERIENCE

DEV MOUNTAIN - Junior Web Developer / Mentor

Summer 2015

- Completed full-time, three-month web development bootcamp
- Gained strong understanding of JavaScript and full-stack (MEAN) methodologies

PLEASANT GROVE CITY - Prosecutor

Jun 2014 - May 2015

- Prosecuted all stages of all criminal cases for the city, averaging over 900 annually, from charging and negotiation to trial and probation reviews
- Coordinated with law enforcement, victim advocates, other attorneys, and judges

UTAH COUNTY GOVT – Law Clerk & Attorney

Mar 2014 - April 2015

- Substituted in court as needed; wrote and edited felony motions, briefs, and memos
- Supervised the workflow of a team of interns

BYU, LINGUISTICS DEPT – Teaching & Research Assistant

Sep 2009 - Nov 2010

- Instructed Perl class often in absence of professor; developed lessons and homework; researched various translation software solutions and text processing applications
- Completed introductory training in Java and C#

BYU, HTRSC – Computer Lab Tech

Dec 2008 - Nov 2011

- Maintained hardware and software in 5 labs (40 computers each) with team
- Assisted students and professors with computers, programming, printing, etc.

EDUCATION

Brigham Young University Law School Juris Doctor Dec 2013
Brigham Young University BA Linguistics Computing Apr 2011

PERSONAL

{ tech, hiking, photography, gardening, racquetball, woodwork, cooking } with family and friends